MD.SAIFUL ISLAM

Address: House -314/kha, Ulon Road, West Rampura, Dhaka-

1219

Primary Mobile No: 01712492178
Primary Email: sohel_bmc@yahoo.com



Career Summary:

About 12.5 years of experience in Supply Chain Management, Procurement & Commercial.

Special Qualification:

Professional in Supply Chain Management

1. Manager (Procurement & Logistics) - (May, 2022 - Continuing) Sanyo Engineering & Construction Inc (Company of Japan)

Responsibilities:

Local Procurement and foreign procurement and logistics function

Negotiation with the local and foreign vendor for getting better price maintaining quality.

Plan, Organizes, directs and control activities related to the procurement & Logistics function.

Manage, coach and develop a high performing team that meets agreed objectives and delivers best practice results added value and continuous improvements.

Set departmental objectives/KPI and review and assess ongoing performance of direct reports.

Maintain appropriate supply chain strategy to maximize customer satisfaction at the lowest possible cost. Monitoring to issue Purchase Order and timely delivery for Local and foreign procurement.

Risk Management. Strategic planning set up regarding procurement & purchasing Effectiveness and efficient analysis regarding supply chain cost.

Taking better decision regarding supply chain of materials and others.

Cost to the procurement/landed cost calculate, represent agenda for procurement decision.

Monitoring & Handling Letter of Credit (LC), Collaboration with foreign Suppliers regarding PFI & others documents,

Customs clearing, Checking all the Financial & shipping documents of LC .Planning, look after car facilities, agreements, and others procurement.

Coordinates with accounts section & Project Analyze market and delivery systems in order to assess present and future material availability. Direct and coordinate activities to purchase all kind of Raw materials, spare parts, Capital Machinery.

Monitoring purchase orders/ work orders follow up delivery, settling supplier bills and payment Issuance of PI, L/C open, amendment/correction, shipment, negotiation, release etc.

Implement supplier lists, price lists, conduct price controls and market research.

Maintain proper liaison with concerned agencies, trade bodies, banks, shipping line, C&F agents, transport agents, insurance companies, Customs etc.

Manage different regulatory requirements with Customs

Support business in the development of supply chain policies, procedures and processes and Contribute to supply chain planning. Ensure efficiency in inventory management with proper uses of different methods (LIFO, FIFO etc.)

Establish ordering system of materials by following EOQ (Economy Order Quantity) considering lead time, MOQ (Minimum Oder Quantity).

Monitor deviations from budget, take corrective actions, coordinate physical inventory counts and report to top management. Devised and implemented short- and long-term procurement plans, policies and practices and effectively communicated the same to team members to ensure achievement of strategic objectives.

Prepare purchase (Local & Overseas) plan and Vendor survey report, Management report, projected budget, etc Monitoring to Purchase all kind of Raw materials, spare parts, Capital Machinery for all concerns Department.

1. Assistant Manager (in Charge) -Supply Chain Management. (4th Feb 2021 – 17 May,22) MAN Energy Solution Ltd (Company ofGermany-Multinational)

Duties/Responsibilities

To lead the team, planning for Local Procurement and foreign procurement

To prepare budget for Local & Foreign.

Negotiation with the Local & Foreign vendor for getting better price maintaining quality.

Effectiveness and efficient analysis regarding supply chain cost.

Risk Management, Monitoring right time, Price, Quantity, place.

Monitoring right time, right Price, right Quantity, right place and

Monitoring to ensure delivery right quality.

Monitoring to manage Fraud Management Strategic planning set up regarding procurement & purchasing.

Effectiveness and efficient analysis regarding supply chain cost.

Taking better decision regarding supply chain of materials and

others. Monitoring & handling Letter of Credit(LC),

Collaboration with foreign Suppliers regarding PFI & others need. Customs clearing.

Checking all the Financial & shipping documents of LC

Planning, look after car facilities, agreements, and others procurement and administration work.

Analyze market and delivery systems in order to assess present and future material availability.

Direct and coordinate activities of personnel engaged in buying, and distributing materials, equipment, machinery, and supplies.

Monitoring materials quality and Source analysis.

Direct and coordinate activities of personnel engaged in buying, and distributing materials, equipment, machinery, and supplies.

Monitoring purchase orders/ work orders follow up delivery, settling supplier bills and payment.

Issuance of PI, L/C open, amendment/correction, shipment, negotiation, release etc.

Implement supplier lists, price lists, conduct price controls and market research.

Maintain proper liaison with concerned agencies, trade bodies, banks, shipping line, C&F agents, transport agents, insurance companies, Customs etc.

Ensure efficiency in inventory management with proper uses of different methods (LIFO, FIFO etc.)

Establish ordering system of materials by following EOQ (Economy Order Quantity) considering lead time, MOQ

Monitor deviations from budget, take corrective actions, coordinate physical inventory counts and report to top management

Devised and implemented short- and long-term procurement plans, policies and practices and

effectively communicated the same to team members to ensure achievement of strategic objectives.

Prepare purchase (Local & Overseas) plan and Vendor survey report, Management report, projected budget, etc

2. Assistant Manager (In Charge)-Supply ChainManagement

GEMCON GROUP (Concern -Real Estate, Govt. Construction, Engineering, Meena bazar, Kazi&Kazi Tea etc.). Dhaka Duties/Responsibilities

Follow up records of goods ordered and received.

To prepare Plan & budget for Local & Foreign.

Negotiation with the vendor for getting better price maintaining quality

Effectiveness and efficient analysis regarding supply chain cost.

Risk Management.

Monitoring right time, right Price, right Quantity, right place and

Monitoring to ensure delivery right quality.

Monitoring to manage Fraud Management Strategic planning set up regarding procurement & purchasing.

Effectiveness and efficient analysis regarding supply chain cost.

Locate vendors of materials, equipment or supplies, and interview them in order to determine product availability and terms of sales.

Monitoring to prepare and process requisitions and purchase orders for supplies and equipment.

Prepare and Control purchasing department budgets.

Review purchase order claims and contracts for conformance to company policy.

Analyze market and delivery systems in order to assess present and future material availability.

Develop and implement purchasing and contract management instructions, policies, and procedures.

Participate in the development of specifications for equipment, products or substitute materials.

Resolve vendor or contractor grievances, and claims against suppliers.

Represent companies in negotiating contracts and formulating policies with suppliers. ---Review, evaluate, and approve specifications for issuing and awarding bids.

Direct and coordinate activities of personnel engaged in buying, and distributing materials, equipment, machinery, and supplies.

Taking better decision regarding supply chain of materials and others.

Maintain proper liaison with concerned agencies, trade bodies, banks, shipping line, C&F agents, transport agents, insurance companies, Customs etc

Executive Purchase (0.5 Years) (July, 2011 - January, 2012), Sky View Developer Limited Duties/Responsibilities

To purchase of construction materials for real estate. and to maintain minimum stock of materials. To calculate minimum cost of procurement

4. Executive Purchase (0.9 Years) (July, 2010 - June, 2011), Electra International Limited Duties/Responsibilities

Local materials purchase. And maintains minimum stock of materials.

Academic Qualification:

Exam Title	Concentration / Major	Institute	Result	Pass. Year	Duration	Achievement
	Procurement &	Chartered Institute of				
CIPS-Level 4	Supply	Procurement & Supply-UK	Enrolled	2021	Continue	-
Post Graduate	Supply Chain	Bangladesh Institute of				Successfully
Diploma (PGD)	Management	ManagementStudies	Pass	2020	6 Month	complete
						(82% marks)
Master of		National University	Second Class,			
Business	Accounting		Marks	2011	1 year	N/A
Studies (MBS)			:58%			
		National University	Second Class,			
BBS (Honours)	Accounting		Marks	2009	4 years	
			:59.27%			
	Business Studies	Upashahor	CGPA:3.9		2 years	
HSC		Degree College, Jessore	out of 5	2003		0

Professional Training:

Training Title	Topic	Institute	Country	Location	Year	Duration
	Commercial Function with					
Foreign	Bank, Customs, C& F Agent,					03 week
Procurement /Import	Logistics & Shipping	Bdjobs	Bangladesh	Dhaka	2021	
Training on VAT	Details on VAT	Dr.Md.AbdurRauf ,Director of NBR	Bangladesh	Dhaka	2014	1 day

Professional Certification:

Certification	Institute	Location	From	То
CIPS-Level 4	Chartered Institute of	UK & Singapore -through	November1,	June 30,
CIPS-Level 4	Procurement and Supply	online	2021	2022
	Bangladesh Institute of Management Studies	Dhaka	01 Jan, 2020	October , 2020

Career and application information:

Preferred Job Category : Supply Chain Management / Procurement / Commercial

Looking For : Managerial Level Job

Available For : Full Time

Preferred District : Anywhere in Bangladesh.

Preferred Organization Types : Real Estate, Group of Companies, Manufacturing (FMCG),

Multinational Companies, Buying House,

PersonalDetails:

Father's Name : Md.Shahjahan Sardar Mother's Name : Nurjahan Begum Date of Birth : November 21, 1985

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Bangladeshis

Religion : Islam

Permanent Address : kachua, Banaripara, Banaripara, Barishal 8530

Family Friend

Current Location : Dhaka

Reference (s):

Reference: 01 Reference: 02 Name Rezaul Islam Mamun Abul Hossain Single Proprietorship Business Organization **Trade House** Designation Manager Owner Address Road 4/A, Dhanmondi, Dhaka Kashimpur, Gazipur 01712720498 01915206081 Mobile

Relative

Signature

Relation